rankedboost.com 2019-11-11

# Privacy Policy - RankedBoost

**PRIVACY POLICY**

 **Last updated May 24, 2018 ** 

Thank you for choosing to be part of our community at Ranked Boost, LLC (“ **Company** ”, “ **we** ”, “ **us** ”, or “ **our** ”). We are committed to protecting your personal information and your right to privacy. If you have any questions or concerns about our policy, or our practices with regards to your personal information, please contact us at support@rankedboost.com.

When you visit our website https://rankedboost.com/, mobile application, and use our services, you trust us with your personal information. We take your privacy very seriously. In this privacy notice, we describe our privacy policy. We seek to explain to you in the clearest way possible what information we collect, how we use it and what rights you have in relation to it. We hope you take some time to read through it carefully, as it is important. If there are any terms in this privacy policy that you do not agree with, please discontinue use of our Sites or Apps and our services.

This privacy policy applies to all information collected through our website (such as https://rankedboost.com/), mobile application, (" **Apps** "), and/or any related services, sales, marketing or events (we refer to them collectively in this privacy policy as the " **Sites** "). 

 **Please read this privacy policy carefully as it will help you make informed decisions about sharing your personal information with us.  ** 

 **TABLE OF CONTENTS  ** 

1\. WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT?

2\. HOW DO WE USE YOUR INFORMATION?

3\. WILL YOUR INFORMATION BE SHARED WITH ANYONE?  

4\. WHO WILL YOUR INFORMATION BE SHARED WITH?    

5\. DO WE USE COOKIES AND OTHER TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES?     

6\. HOW DO WE HANDLE YOUR SOCIAL LOGINS?    

7\. WHAT IS OUR STANCE ON THIRD-PARTY WEBSITES?  

8\. HOW LONG DO WE KEEP YOUR INFORMATION?

9\. HOW DO WE KEEP YOUR INFORMATION SAFE?  

10\. DO WE COLLECT INFORMATION FROM MINORS?  

11\. WHAT ARE YOUR PRIVACY RIGHTS?

12\. CONTROLS FOR DO-NOT-TRACK FEATURES 

13\. DO CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS HAVE SPECIFIC PRIVACY RIGHTS? 

14\. DO WE MAKE UPDATES TO THIS POLICY?

15\. HOW CAN YOU CONTACT US ABOUT THIS POLICY?

 **1\. WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT?  ** 

 **Personal information you disclose to us**  

 ** _In Short:_  ** _We collect personal information that you provide to us such as name, address, contact information, passwords and security data, payment information, and social media login data_.  

We collect personal information that you voluntarily provide to us when registering at the Sites or Apps, expressing an interest in obtaining information about us or our products and services, when participating in activities on the Sites or  Apps (such as posting messages in our online forums or entering competitions, contests or giveaways) or otherwise contacting us.

The personal information that we collect depends on the context of your interactions with us and the Sites or Apps, the choices you make and the products and features you use. The personal information we collect can include the following:

 **Name and Contact Data.**  We collect your first and last name, email address, postal address, phone number, and other similar contact data.

 **Credentials.**  We collect passwords, password hints, and similar security information used for authentication and account access.

 **Payment Data.**  We collect data necessary to process your payment if you make purchases, such as your payment instrument number (such as a credit card number), and the security code associated with your payment instrument. All payment data is stored by our payment processor and you should review its privacy policies and contact the payment processor directly to respond to your questions.  

 **Social Media Login Data.**  We provide you with the option to register using social media account details, like your Facebook, Twitter or other social media account. If you choose to register in this way, we will collect the Information described in the section called "HOW DO WE HANDLE YOUR SOCIAL LOGINS " below.  

All personal information that you provide to us must be true, complete and accurate, and you must notify us of any changes to such personal information.   

 **Information automatically collected**  

 ** _In Short:_  ** _Some information – such as IP address and/or browser and device characteristics – is collected automatically when you visit our Sites or Apps._

We automatically collect certain information when you visit, use or navigate the Sites or Apps. This information does not reveal your specific identity (like your name or contact information) but may include device and usage information, such as your IP address, browser and device characteristics, operating system, language preferences, referring URLs, device name, country, location, information about how and when you use our Sites or Apps and other technical information. This information is primarily needed to maintain the security and operation of our Sites or Apps, and for our internal analytics and reporting purposes.

Like many businesses, we also collect information through cookies and similar technologies. You can find out more about this in our Cookies Policy: https://rankedboost.com/privacy/.   

 **Information collected through our Apps**  

 ** _In Short:_   ** _We may collect information regarding your push notifications, when you use our apps._

If you use our Apps, we may also collect the following information:  

*  _Push Notifications._  We may request to send you push notifications regarding your account or the mobile application. If you wish to opt-out from receiving these types of communications, you may turn them off in your device’s settings.       

 **Information collected from other sources**  

 ** _In Short:  _ ** _We may collect limited data from public databases, marketing partners, social media platforms, and other outside sources. _  

We may obtain information about you from other sources, such as public databases, joint marketing partners, social media platforms (such as Facebook), as well as from other third parties. Examples of the information we receive from other sources include: social media profile information (your name, gender, birthday, email, current city, state and country, user identification numbers for your contacts, profile picture URL and any other information that you choose to make public); marketing leads and search results and links, including paid listings (such as sponsored links).  

 **2\. HOW DO WE USE YOUR INFORMATION?  ** 

 ** _In Short:  _ ** _We process your information for purposes based on legitimate business interests, the fulfillment of our contract with you, compliance with our legal obligations, and/or your consent._   

We use personal information collected via our Sites or Apps for a variety of business purposes described below. We process your personal information for these purposes in reliance on our legitimate business interests, in order to enter into or perform a contract with you, with your consent, and/or for compliance with our legal obligations. We indicate the specific processing grounds we rely on next to each purpose listed below.  

We use the information we collect or receive:  

  *  **To facilitate account creation and logon process.**  If you choose to link your account with us to a third party account *(such as your Google or Facebook account), we use the information you allowed us to collect from those third parties to facilitate account creation and logon process. See the section below headed " HOW DO WE HANDLE YOUR SOCIAL LOGINS " for further information.        
  *  **To send you marketing and promotional communications.**  We and/or our third party marketing partners may use the personal information you send to us for our marketing purposes, if this is in accordance with your marketing preferences. You can opt-out of our marketing emails at any time (see the " WHAT ARE YOUR PRIVACY RIGHTS " below).       
  *  **To send administrative information to you.  **We may use your personal information to send you product, service and new feature information and/or information about changes to our terms, conditions, and policies.         
  *  **Fulfill and manage your orders.**  We may use your information to fulfill and manage your orders, payments, returns, and exchanges made through the Sites or Apps.           
  *  **To post testimonials.**  We post testimonials on our Sites or Apps that may contain personal information. Prior to posting a testimonial, we will obtain your consent to use your name and testimonial. If you wish to update, or delete your testimonial, please contact us at privacy@rankedboost.com and be sure to include your name, testimonial location, and contact information.            
  *  **Deliver targeted advertising to you.  **We may use your information to develop and display content and advertising (and work with third parties who do so) tailored to your interests and/or location and to measure its effectiveness.For more information, see our Cookie Policy: https://rankedboost.com/cookie-policy/.                
  *  **Administer prize draws and competitions.  **We may use your information to administer prize draws and competitions when you elect to participate in competitions.               
  *  **Request Feedback.**  We may use your information to request feedback and to contact you about your use of our Sites or Apps.                  
  *  **To protect our Sites.**  We may use your information as part of our efforts to keep our Sites or Apps safe and secure (for example, for fraud monitoring and prevention).                     
  *  **To enable user-to-user communications.**  We may use your information in order to enable user-to-user communications with each user's consent.                       
  *  **To enforce our terms, conditions and policies.**            
  *  **To respond to legal requests and prevent harm.  **If we receive a subpoena or other legal request, we may need to inspect the data we hold to determine how to respond.                          
  *  **For other Business Purposes.**  We may use your information for other Business Purposes, such as data analysis, identifying usage trends, determining the effectiveness of our promotional campaigns and to evaluate and improve our Sites or Apps, products, services, marketing and your experience.                             

 **3\. WILL YOUR INFORMATION BE SHARED WITH ANYONE?  ** 

 ** _In Short:  _ ** _We only share information with your consent, to comply with laws, to protect your rights, or to fulfill business obligations.  _  

We may process or share data based on the following legal basis:

  *  **Consent:** We may process your data if you have given us specific consent to use your personal information in a specific purpose. 
  *  **Legitimate Interests:** We may process your data when it is reasonably necessary to achieve our legitimate business interests. 
  *  **Performance of a Contract:  **Where we have entered into a contract with you, we may process your personal information to fulfill the terms of our contract. 
  *  **Legal Obligations:** We may disclose your information where we are legally required to do so in order to comply with applicable law, governmental requests, a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process, such as in response to a court order or a subpoena (including in response to public authorities to meet national security or law enforcement requirements). 
  *  **Vital Interests:** We may disclose your information where we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding potential violations of our policies, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the safety of any person and illegal activities, or as evidence in litigation in which we are involved.

More specifically, we may need to process your data or share your personal information in the following situations:   

  *  **Vendors, Consultants and Other Third-Party Service Providers.**  We may share your data with third party vendors, service providers, contractors or agents who perform services for us or on our behalf and require access to such information to do that work. Examples include: payment processing, data analysis, email delivery, hosting services, customer service and marketing efforts. We may allow selected third parties to use tracking technology on the Sites or Apps, which will enable them to collect data about how you interact with the Sites or Apps over time. This information may be used to, among other things, analyze and track data, determine the popularity of certain content and better understand online activity. Unless described in this Policy, we do not share, sell, rent or trade any of your information with third parties for their promotional purposes.    
  *  **Business Transfers.**  We may share or transfer your information in connection with, or during negotiations of, any merger, sale of company assets, financing, or acquisition of all or a portion of our business to another company.  
  *  **Third-Party Advertisers.**  We may use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit the Sites or Apps. These companies may use information about your visits to our Website(s) and other websites that are contained in web cookies and other tracking technologies in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. See our Cookie Policy: https://rankedboost.com/privacy/ for further information.      
  *  **Affiliates.**  We may share your information with our affiliates, in which case we will require those affiliates to honor this privacy policy. Affiliates include our parent company and any subsidiaries, joint venture partners or other companies that we control or that are under common control with us.       
  *  **Business Partners.**  We may share your information with our business partners to offer you certain products, services or promotions.      
  *  **Other Users.**  When you share personal information (for example, by posting comments, contributions or other content to the Sites or Apps) or otherwise interact with public areas of the Sites or Apps, such personal information may be viewed by all users and may be publicly distributed outside the Sites or Apps in perpetuity. If you interact with other users of our Sites or Apps and register through a social network (such as Facebook), your contacts on the social network will see your name, profile photo, and descriptions of your activity. Similarly, other users will be able to view descriptions of your activity, communicate with you within our Sites or Apps, and view your profile.    

 **4\. WHO WILL YOUR INFORMATION BE SHARED WITH?  ** 

 ** _In Short:  _ ** _We only share information with the following third parties._   

We only share and disclose your information with the following third parties. We have categorized each party so that you may be easily understand the purpose of our data collection and processing practices. If we have processed your data based on your consent and you wish to revoke your consent, please contact us.  

  *  **Advertising, Direct Marketing, and Lead Generation**  
Google AdSense, DoubleClick for Publishers, AdMob, Media.net, Taboola and Venatus Media

  *  **Affiliate Marketing Programs**  
Amazon Affiliates

  *  **Allow Users to Connect to their Third-Party Accounts**  
, Battle.net account, Facebook account, Twitter account, Instagram account and Youtube account

  *  **Content Optimization  **  
Google Site Search and YouTube video embed

  *  **Functionality and Infrastructure Optimization**  
Cloudflare, Termly.io, CDN and Gleam.io

  *  **Invoice and Billing**  
Stripe, and Amazon Pay

  *  **User Account Registration and Authentication**  
Facebook Login, Twitch Authentication, Instagram Authentication and YouTube OAuth 2.0

  *  **Web and Mobile Analytics**  
Google Analytics

  *  **Website Hosting**  
WordPress.com

 **5\. DO WE USE COOKIES AND OTHER TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES?  ** 

 ** _In Short:  _ ** _We may use cookies and other tracking technologies to collect and store your information._   

We may use cookies and similar tracking technologies (like web beacons and pixels) to access or store information. Specific information about how we use such technologies and how you can refuse certain cookies is set out in our Cookie Policy: https://rankedboost.com/privacy/.

 **6\. HOW DO WE HANDLE YOUR SOCIAL LOGINS?  ** 

 ** _In Short:  _ ** _If you choose to register or log in to our websites using a social media account, we may have access to certain information about you._   

Our Sites or Apps offer you the ability to register and login using your third party social media account details (like your Facebook or Twitter logins). Where you choose to do this, we will receive certain profile information about you from your social media provider. The profile Information we receive may vary depending on the social media provider concerned, but will often include your name, e-mail address, friends list, profile picture as well as other information you choose to make public.         

We will use the information we receive only for the purposes that are described in this privacy policy or that are otherwise made clear to you on the Sites or Apps. Please note that we do not control, and are not responsible for, other uses of your personal information by your third party social media provider. We recommend that you review their privacy policy to understand how they collect, use and share your personal information, and how you can set your privacy preferences on their sites and apps.         

 **7\. WHAT IS OUR STANCE ON THIRD-PARTY WEBSITES?  ** 

 ** _In Short:  _ ** _We are not responsible for the safety of any information that you share with third-party providers who advertise, but are not affiliated with, our websites.  _  

The Sites or Apps may contain advertisements from third parties that are not affiliated with us and which may link to other websites, online services or mobile applications. We cannot guarantee the safety and privacy of data you provide to any third parties. Any data collected by third parties is not covered by this privacy policy. We are not responsible for the content or privacy and security practices and policies of any third parties, including other websites, services or applications that may be linked to or from the Sites or Apps. You should review the policies of such third parties and contact them directly to respond to your questions.        

 **8\. HOW LONG DO WE KEEP YOUR INFORMATION?  ** 

 ** _In Short:  _ ** _We keep your information for as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this privacy policy unless otherwise required by law._   

We will only keep your personal information for as long as it is necessary for the purposes set out in this privacy policy, unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law (such as tax, accounting or other legal requirements). No purpose in this policy will require us keeping your personal information for longer than 1 year past the termination of the user's account. 

When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your personal information, we will either delete or anonymize it, or, if this is not possible (for example, because your personal information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your personal information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible.

 **9\. HOW DO WE KEEP YOUR INFORMATION SAFE?   ** 

 ** _In Short:  _ ** _We aim to protect your personal information through a system of organizational and technical security measures._   

We have implemented appropriate technical and organizational security measures designed to protect the security of any personal information we process. However, please also remember that we cannot guarantee that the internet itself is 100% secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal information, transmission of personal information to and from our Sites or Apps is at your own risk. You should only access the services within a secure environment. 

 **10\. DO WE COLLECT INFORMATION FROM MINORS?  ** 

 ** _In Short:  _ ** _We do not knowingly collect data from or market to children under 18 years of age._   

We do not knowingly solicit data from or market to children under 18 years of age. By using the Sites or Apps, you represent that you are at least 18 or that you are the parent or guardian of such a minor and consent to such minor dependent’s use of the Sites or Apps. If we learn that personal information from users less than 18 years of age has been collected, we will deactivate the account and take reasonable measures to promptly delete such data from our records. If you become aware of any data we have collected from children under age 18, please contact us at privacy@rankedboost.com.  

 **11\. WHAT ARE YOUR PRIVACY RIGHTS?  ** 

 ** _In Short:  _ ** _In some regions, such as the European Economic Area, you have rights that allow you greater access to and control over your personal information. You may review, change, or terminate your account at any time._   

In some regions (like the European Economic Area), you have certain rights under applicable data protection laws. These may include the right (i) to request access and obtain a copy of your personal information, (ii) to request rectification or erasure; (iii) to restrict the processing of your personal information; and (iv) if applicable, to data portability. In certain circumstances, you may also have the right to object to the processing of your personal information. To make such a request, please use the contact details  provided below. We will consider and act upon any request in accordance with applicable data protection laws. 

If we are relying on your consent to process your personal information, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. Please note however that this will not affect the lawfulness of the processing before its withdrawal.   

If you are resident in the European Economic Area and you believe we are unlawfully processing your personal information, you also have the right to complain to your local data protection supervisory authority. You can find their contact details here: [http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/index_en.htm](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/index_en.htm)    

 **Account Information**   

If you would at any time like to review or change the information in your account or terminate your account, you can:  

■  Log into your account settings and update your user account.   

■  You may also view the data RankedBoost stores about you and request to have it deleted or anonimized here: https://rankedboost.com/privacy-tools/   

■  Contact us using the contact information provided.   

Upon your request to terminate your account, we will deactivate or delete your account and information from our active databases. However, some information may be retained in our files to prevent fraud, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigations, enforce our Terms of Use and/or comply with legal requirements.     

 ** _Cookies and similar technologies:_  **Most Web browsers are set to accept cookies by default. If you prefer, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove cookies and to reject cookies. If you choose to remove cookies or reject cookies, this could affect certain features or services of our Sites or Apps. To opt-out of interest-based advertising by advertisers on our Sites or  Apps visit  [http://www.aboutads.info/choices/](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) . For further information, please see our Cookie Policy: https://rankedboost.com/privacy/.        

 ** _Opting out of email marketing:_  **You can unsubscribe from our marketing email list at any time by clicking on the unsubscribe link in the emails that we send or by contacting us using the details provided below. You will then be removed from the marketing email list – however, we will still need to send you service-related emails that are necessary for the administration and use of your account. To otherwise opt-out, you may:  

■  Note your preferences when you register an account with the site.   

■  Access your account settings and update preferences.   

■  Contact us using the contact information provided.   

 **12\. CONTROLS FOR DO-NOT-TRACK FEATURES  ** 

Most web browsers and some mobile operating systems and mobile applications include a Do-Not-Track (“DNT”) feature or setting you can activate to signal your privacy preference not to have data about your online browsing activities monitored and collected. No uniform technology standard for recognizing and implementing DNT signals has been finalized. As such, we do not currently respond to DNT browser signals or any other mechanism that automatically communicates your choice not to be tracked online. If a standard for online tracking is adopted that we must follow in the future, we will inform you about that practice in a revised version of this Privacy Policy. 

 **13\. DO CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS HAVE SPECIFIC PRIVACY RIGHTS?  ** 

 ** _In Short:  _ ** _Yes, if you are a resident of California, you are granted specific rights regarding access to your personal information.  _  

California Civil Code Section 1798.83, also known as the “Shine The Light” law, permits our users who are California residents to request and obtain from us, once a year and free of charge, information about categories of personal information (if any) we disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes and the names and addresses of all third parties with which we shared personal information in the immediately preceding calendar year. If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please submit your request in writing to us using the contact information provided below. 

If you are under 18 years of age, reside in California, and have a registered account with the Sites or Apps, you have the right to request removal of unwanted data that you publicly post on the Sites or Apps. To request removal of such data, please contact us using the contact information provided below, and include the email address associated with your account and a statement that you reside in California. We will make sure the data is not publicly displayed on the Sites or Apps, but please be aware that the data may not be completely or comprehensively removed from our systems.

 **14\. DO WE MAKE UPDATES TO THIS POLICY?  ** 

 ** _In Short:  _ ** _Yes, we will update this policy as necessary to stay compliant with relevant laws._   

We may update this privacy policy from time to time. The updated version will be indicated by an updated “Revised” date and the updated version will be effective as soon as it is accessible. If we make material changes to this privacy policy, we may notify you either by prominently posting a notice of such changes or by directly sending you a notification. We encourage you to review this privacy policy frequently to be informed of how we are protecting your information. 

 **15\. HOW CAN YOU CONTACT US ABOUT THIS POLICY?  ** 

If you have questions or comments about this policy, you may contact our Data Protection Officer (DPO), Yaroslav Sergey, by email at privacy@rankedboost.com, or by post to:

Ranked Boost, LLC    

Yaroslav Sergey

222 S MAIN, Suite 500

Salt Lake City, UT 84101

United States    

If you are a resident in the European Economic Area, the "data controller" of your personal information is Ranked Boost, LLC. Ranked Boost, LLC has appointed Yaroslav Sergey to be its representative in the EEA. You can contact them directly regarding the processing of your information by Ranked Boost, LLC, by email at privacy@rankedboost.com, or by post to:

222 S MAIN, Suite 500

Salt Lake City 84101

Belgium

###  How can you review, update, or delete the data we collect from you? 

Based on the laws of some countries, you may have the right to request access to the personal information we collect from you, change that information, or delete it in some circumstances. To request to review, update, or delete your personal information, please submit a request form by clicking [here](https://rankedboost.com/privacy-tools/). We will respond to your request within 30 days. 

### How you can control the information sent to Google

For tips and advice on staying safe and managing your data online, visit the [Google Safety Center.](http://www.google.com/safetycenter/)

Here are some of the ways you can control the information that is shared by your web browser when you visit or interact with Google services on partners’ sites across the web: 

  * [Ads Settings](http://www.google.com/safetycenter/tools/#manage-your-ads-preferences) helps you control the ads by Google that you see across the web. You can learn how ads are selected for you, opt out of certain categories and block specific advertisers. Learn more about [advertising](http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/).
  * Many sites across the web use Google Analytics to understand how visitors engage with their sites or apps. If you don’t want Analytics to be used in your browser, you can [install the Google Analytics browser add-on](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). Learn more about [Google Analytics and privacy](http://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en).
  * Google makes it easy for you to make recommendations for your friends – for example, by clicking the +1 button on content you like. Some of your +1s may show your name and Google+ profile photo in ads, but you can [opt out](http://plus.google.com/settings/endorsements) if you don’t want to appear in ads. You can also visit the +1 tab on your Google+ profile to review and manage all of your +1’s. [Learn more](http://support.google.com/plus/answer/1047397?p=sign_up_about_plusones&rd=2&hl=en) about how to get to your +1 tab.
  * [Incognito mode in Chrome](http://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95464?hl=en) allows you to browse the web without recording webpages and files in your browser history. Cookies are deleted after you’ve closed all of your incognito windows and tabs, and your bookmarks and settings are stored until you delete them. Learn more about [cookies.](http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/cookies/)

### What are Ads by Google?

Ads by Google are keyword-targeted advertisements provided through the Google AdWords™ program. These listings are administered, sorted and maintained by Google. For information about these Google ads, go to [adwords.google.com](http://adwords.google.com/). Third party supplied ads are not the rankedboost.com responsibility. Google may place or recognize a unique “cookie” on your Web browser. Information from this cookie may be used by Google to help provide advertisers with more targeted advertising opportunities. For more information about Google’s privacy policy, including how to opt out, go to [www.google.com/ads/preferences](http://www.google.com/ads/preferences). By clicking on Advertiser Links you will leave rankedboost.com. The Web site you will go to is not endorsed by the rankedboost.com.
